Finding aid for the Aldous and Laura Huxley papers, 1925-2007 LSC.2009
UCLA Library Special Collections
- Laura Huxley Papers
  - Psychedelics
    - Recordings
      - Label reads " W.P. Aug 30 - 200" [LSD session with Laura Huxley and unidentified man?; related to UCLA Tape No 408 & 414 - part III], no date; UCLA Tape No. 410
      - Label reads: Laura, LSD, Dec 16, Tape A, 1963 Dec 16; UCLA Tape No. 378A; Laura Huxley, LSD session
      - Label reads: L.H. [Laura Huxley], Dec 16-63, LSD 100mcg, Tape B, 1963 Dec 16; UCLA Tape No. 378B; Laura Huxley, LSD session
      - Label reads" D.N. = 10 15…200" [LSD session with Laura Huxley and unidentified man?; related to UCLA Tape No. 414 & 410], no date; UCLA Tape No. 408
      - Unlabeled; Laura Huxley and unidentified man talking [possible LSD sesssion?], no date; UCLA Tape No. 409
      - Label reads: G.P., LSD 300mcg, 4-5 Dec 1970, 1970 Dec 4-5; UCLA Tape No. 396A
      - Label reads: G.P., LSD 300mcg, 4-5 Dec 1970, 1970 Dec 4-5; UCLA Tape No. 396D; Continuation of 396C.
      - Label reads: G.P., LSD 300mcg, 4-5 Dec 1970, 1970 Dec 4-5; UCLA Tape No. 396G; Continuation of 396F.
      - Label reads: G.P., LSD 300mcg, 4-5 Dec 1970, 1970 Dec 4-5; UCLA Tape No. 396E; Continuation of 396D.
      - Label reads: G.P., LSD 300mcg, 4-5 Dec 1970, 1970 Dec 4-5; UCLA Tape No. 396C; Continuation of 396B.
      - Label reads: G.P., LSD 300mcg, 4-5 Dec 1970, 1970 Dec 4-5; UCLA Tape No. 396B; Continuation of 396A.
      - Label reads: G.P., LSD 300mcg, 4-5 Dec 1970, 1970 Dec 4-5; UCLA Tape No. 396F; Continuation of 396E.
      - Laura Huxley, Annual Conference of the Association for Transpersonal Psychology, Thresholds of Creativity: Eros, Shadow and Spirit, Psychedelic Experience at the Turn of the Millennium, Monterey, CA, 1997 Aug; UCLA Tape No. 261A (Box 102)
      - Laura Huxley, Annual Conference of the Association for Transpersonal Psychology, Thresholds of Creativity: Eros, Shadow and Spirit, Psychedelic Experience at the Turn of the Millennium, Monterey, CA (continued from UCLA Tape No. 261 A), 1997 Aug; UCLA Tape No. 261B (Box 102)
      - Laura Huxley, Psychedelics, LA Weekly (continued from UCLA Tape No. 262 A), 1998 Apr 30; UCLA Tape No. 262B (Box 102, Folder unknown container)
      - Laura Huxley, Psychedelics, LA Weekly, 1998 Apr 30; UCLA Tape No. 262A (Box 102, Folder unknown container)
      - Laura Huxley, Annual Conference of the Association for Transpersonal Psychology, Thresholds of Creativity: Eros, Shadow and Spirit, Psychedelic Experience at the Turn of the Millennium, Monterey, CA, 1997 Aug; UCLA Tape No. 261; sound very faint (Box 102, Folder 1)
      - Laura Huxley, Psychedelics, LA Weekly, 1998 Apr 30; UCLA Tape No. 262 (Box 102, Folder 2)
      - Laura Huxley, Interview, Jamie Alderson, LSD, 1988 Oct 21; UCLA Tape No. 272 (Box 102, Folder 12)
      - Laura Huxley, Psychedelics in the 1990s, Sound Photosynthesis (continued from UCLA Tape No.295 A), 1990 Feb 24; UCLA Tape No. 295B (Box 103, Folder unknown container)
      - Laura Huxley, Psychedelics in the 1990s, Sound Photosynthesis (continued from UCLA Tape No.295 A), 1990 Feb 24; UCLA Tape No. 295C (Box 103, Folder unknown container)
      - Laura Huxley, Psychedelics in the 1990s, Sound Photosynthesis (continued from UCLA Tape No.295 E), 1990 Feb 24; UCLA Tape No. 295G (Box 103, Folder unknown container)
      - Laura Huxley, Psychedelics in the 1990s, Sound Photosynthesis (continued from UCLA Tape No.295 B), 1990 Feb 24; UCLA Tape No. 295D (Box 103, Folder unknown container)
      - Laura Huxley, Psychedelics in the 1990s, Sound Photosynthesis (continued from UCLA Tape No.295 C), 1990 Feb 24; UCLA Tape No. 295E (Box 103, Folder unknown container)
      - Laura Huxley, Psychedelics in the 1990s, Sound Photosynthesis (continued from UCLA Tape No.295 D), 1990 Feb 24; UCLA Tape No. 295F (Box 103, Folder unknown container)
      - Laura Huxley, Psychedelics in the 1990s, Sound Photosynthesis (continued from UCLA Tape No.295 H), 1990 Feb 24; UCLA Tape No. 295I (Box 103, Folder unknown container)
      - Laura Huxley, Psychedelics in the 1990s, Sound Photosynthesis (continued from UCLA Tape No.295 F), 1990 Feb 24; UCLA Tape No. 295H (Box 103, Folder unknown container)
      - Laura Huxley, Psychedelics in the 1990s, Sound Photosynthesis, no date; UCLA Tape No. 295A (Box 103, Folder unknown container)
      - Laura Huxley, Psychedelics in the 1990s, Sound Photosynthesis, 1990 Feb 24; UCLA Tape No. 295 (Box 103, Folder 4)
      - Label reads: 31. Alan Watts Alchemy of LSD, no date; UCLA Tape No. 332 (Box 105, Folder 11)
      - Label reads: G.P., LSD 300mcg, 4-5 Dec 1970, 1970 Dec 4-5; UCLA Tape No. 396 (Box 115, Folder unknown container)
      - Label reads: "G.P. L.S.D. 125 m[illegible…microgams?] Aug 18 64", 18 Aug 1964; UCLA Tape No. 415
      - Unlabeled; [LSD session with Laura Huxley and unidentified man? Part II -related to UCLA Tape No 408 & 410], no date; UCLA Tape No. 414
    - Unger, Sanford
      - Articles and Correspondence, 1963-1969; LSD Type Drugs and Psychedelic Therapy, The Present Status and Direction of Psychedelic LSD Research (Box 29, Folder 18)
    - Video recordings
      - Label reads: "The Bridge: A Psychedelic Sampler; The Bridge Conference Linking the Past, Present, and Future of Psychedelics; featured speakers: Timothy Leary and Terence McKenna, " Stanford, 1991 Feb 2-3; UCLA Tape No. 459; VHS tape (Box 109, Folder 4)
      - Label reads: "The 2001 International Conference on Altered States of Consciousness; Bruce Eisner, The History and Future of LSD", UCLA Tape No. 460; VHS tape (Box 109, Folder 5)
      - Label reads: "The 2001 International Conference on Altered States of Consciousness; Bruce Eisner, MDMA and Human Nature, Albuquerque", UCLA Tape No. 461; VHS tape (Box 109, Folder 6)
  - Research / Professional / Projects
    - Awards
      - Awards, ceremony programs and correspondence, 1978-2003 (Box 37, Folder 14)
    - Education
      - Correspondence and Ephemera, 1977-1983 (Box 37, Folder 1)
    - Health
      - Clippings, articles relating to medicine, health, psychology and the environment [1 of 2], 1960s-1970s; oversize box (Box 52, Folder 2)
      - Clippings, articles relating to birth control, alternative medicine and technology [2 of 2], 1960s-1970s; oversize box; includes article on Ernest Hemingway, Life Magazine, 1961 (Box 52, Folder 3)
    - Interviews
      - Transcripts, no date (Box 31, Folder 7)
    - Lectures
      - Announcements, Pamphlets and Correspondence, 1962-1963 (Box 32, Folder 1)
      - Announcements, Pamphlets and Correspondence, 1963-1969 (Box 32, Folder 2)
      - Transcript and Audio Cassette Tape, "Visionary Common Sense", 26 Aug 1994 (Box 32, Folder 3)
      - Holograph notes, [1960s] (Box 32, Folder 4)
      - Typescripts and holograph notes, [1970s-1990s] (Box 32, Folder 5)
    - Medicine and Health
      - Article, "I Took the Niehans Treatment" by Helen Worden, Vogue, 15 Jan 1966 (Box 38, Folder 3)
      - Correspondence, Articles and Interviews with Laura Huxley, 1963-1984 (Box 38, Folder 4)
      - Interview with Laura Huxley, Somatics, 2004 (Box 38, Folder 5)
    - Mediums
      - Correspondence and holograph notes, 1965-1968 (Box 37, Folder 2)
      - Interview and Transcript, [1964 ?] (Box 37, Folder 3)
    - Mysticism
      - Articles, 1966-1969 (Box 37, Folder 4)
    - Organizations and Programs
      - General Pamphlets, Notes and Ephemera (1 of 2), 1963-1995; includes materials collected by Laura Huxley (Box 31, Folder 5)
      - General Pamphlets, Notes and Ephemera (2 of 2), 1963-1995; includes materials collected by Laura Huxley (Box 31, Folder 6)
    - Our Ultimate Investment
      - Articles, Correspondence and Notes, 1978-1999 (Box 31, Folder 1)
    - Our Ultimate Investment & Project Caress
      - Clippings, articles and interviews [1 of 2], 1970s-1990s; oversize box (Box 54, Folder 3)
      - Clippings, articles and interviews [2 of 2], 1970s-1990s; oversize box (Box 54, Folder 4)
    - Project Awake
      - Draft, Project Awake program description, 1971 (Box 31, Folder 2)
    - Psychiatry and Psychology
      - Articles and Publications, 1962-1979; collected by Laura Huxley (early material possibly owned or collected by Aldous Huxley) (Box 37, Folder 5)
      - Correspondence and Information regarding Professional Practice, 1961-1971 (Box 37, Folder 6)
      - Report on Southern California Counselling Center (Box 37, Folder 7)
      - Poems, "High Psychology"; "Renaiscence Therapy", undated (Box 37, Folder 8)
      - Articles and Questionnaire regarding Psychosynthesis, undated (Box 37, Folder 9)
      - Article, "The Treatment of Patients" by Marie Nyswander, The New Yorker, 26 Jun 1965 (Box 37, Folder 10)
      - Article, "The Incompleat Suicide" by Matthew Huxley, 14 Oct 1965 (Box 37, Folder 11)
      - Article, "So Who Listens" by Matthew Huxley, Mar 1965 (Box 37, Folder 12)
      - Correspondence, 1963-1976 (Box 37, Folder 13)
      - Articles Notes and Correspondence relating to the topic of Schizophrenia (1 of 2), 1970s (Box 38, Folder 1)
      - Articles Notes and Correspondence relating to the topic of Schizophrenia (2 of 2), 1970s (Box 38, Folder 2)
    - Ram Dass
      - Articles and image, collected by Laura Huxley, c. 1977; oversize box (Box 55, Folder 4)
    - Seminars
      - Pamphlets and Notes, 1964-1969 (Box 31, Folder 3)
      - Correspondence, 1964-1969 (Box 31, Folder 4)
    - The Huxley Institute for Biosocial Research
      - Materials relating to the American Schizophrenia Association name change [1 of 2], 1971-1973; includes correspondence from Humphrey Osmond and Juliette Huxley (Box 40, Folder 1)
      - Materials relating to the American Schizophrenia Association name change [2 of 2], 1971-1973; includes correspondence from Humphrey Osmond and Juliette Huxley (Box 40, Folder 2)
      - Correspondence, pamphlets, meeting minutes, statistics reports, pre-1974 (Box 40, Folder 3)
      - Correspondence, pamphlets, meeting minutes, statistics reports, 1974 (Box 40, Folder 4)
      - Correspondence, pamphlets, meeting minutes, statistics reports, 1975 (Box 40, Folder 5)
      - Correspondence, pamphlets, meeting minutes, statistics reports, 1976 (Box 40, Folder 6)
      - Correspondence, pamphlets, meeting minutes, statistics reports, 1977 (Box 40, Folder 7)
      - Correspondence, pamphlets, meeting minutes, statistics reports, 1978-1979 (Box 40, Folder 8)
      - Correspondence, pamphlets, meeting minutes, statistics reports, 1980-1981 (Box 40, Folder 9)
      - Newsletters, 1971-1981 (Box 40, Folder 10)
  - Writings about Laura Huxley
    - Clippings, biographical articles and publicity interviews; includes photocopies, 1920s-1990s; oversize box (Box 53, Folder 6)
- Accession LSC-2009-2009-12 backlog material, LSC-2009-2009-12; 7 Audiovisual Carriers (7 records); 10 Born-digital Carriers (9 optical discs, 1 floppy disk) (Box 120, Box 121)
- Accession LSC-1976-002 backlog material, LSC-1976-002 (Box 122)
- Accession LSC-2013-005 backlog material, LSC-2013-005 (Box 123)
- Accession LSC-2119-2012-10 backlog material, LSC-2119-2012-10; 1 Audiovisual Carriers (1 open reel audiotape) (Box 124)
- Accession LSC-1988-004 backlog material, LSC-1988-004 (Box 125)
- Accession LSC-1990-001 backlog materials, LSC-1990-001 (Box 126)